RG 004:086, Montville Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Montville Probate Court records
1850-2009
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Montville District)
15.5 cubic feet
Record books, 1852-1975; Probate files, 1850-1936; Wills, 1907-2009.
RG004_086
1922-001, 2011-102, and 2014-007
Historical Note
Montville, New London County, Town established on October 12, 1786, Parent Town: New London
The Montville Probate District was constituted on June 27, 1851 from the New London Probate District. The Montville Probate District merged with the East Lyme, Old Lyme, and Salem Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Region #32 Probate District which serves the municipalities of East Lyme, Montville, Old Lyme, and Salem.
Town of Montville, Probate District chronology:
October 1786 - June 26, 1851, New London District
June 27, 1851 - January 4, 2011, Montville District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Region # 32 District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, 1852-1975. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1850-1936. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1850-1936 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Wills, 1907-2009. Includes original wills admitted to probate.
Arrangement
Record books in accession 2014-007 are numbered 1 to 17.
Probate files in accession 1922-001 are arranged alphabetically in one series.
Wills in accession 2011-102 are arranged alphabetically.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. Note: CSL does not hold any original record books. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1922-001 are represented in this index.
Wills: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the wills in accession 2011-102.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Montville
Places:
Montville (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Probate files from 1921-1936 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15.
Accession 2014-007, Record books, 1852-1975, and Accession 2011-102, Wills, 1907-2009, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1-4, 6-7, 1852-1919; probate files, 1850-1915; and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1922-001 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): December 14, 1922 (1850-1922); December 4, 1930 (1906-1930); June 2, 1936 (1911-1936); October 26, 1936 (1911-1936). They were interfiled into one alphabetic sequence.
The wills in accession 2011-102 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on January 19, 2011.
The record books in accession 2014-007 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on July 22, 2013.
Container List
- Record books, 1852-1975; 9 cubic feet (17 volumes); 2014-007
  - Records, 1852-1864 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1864-1881 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1881-1896 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1895-1901 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1889-1912 (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1905-1911 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1911-1919 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1920-1921 (Volume 8)
  - Records, 1925-1930 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1930-1938 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1938-1946 (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1947-1955 (Volume 12)
  - Records, 1955-1862 (Volume 13)
  - Records, 1962-1867 (Volume 14)
  - Records, 1967-1969 (Volume 15)
  - Records, 1970-1973 (Volume 16)
  - Records, 1973-1975 (Volume 17)
- Probate files, 1850-1936; 4.5 cubic feet; 1922-001
  - Achinson - Carlton (Drawer 1)
  - Carter - Freiberg (Drawer 2)
  - French - Miller (Drawer 3)
  - Milliard - Schultz (Drawer 4)
  - Schwartz - Zilko; Miscellaneous (Drawer 5)
- Inventory Control Book, 1850-1936; T003073
  Index of the four accessions of probate files now merged into accession 1922-001
  Date span is coverage
  Also known as the Godard Digest
- Wills, 1907-2009; 2 cubic feet; 2011-102
  - A-M (Box 1)
  - N-Z (Box 2)